<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='oai2.xsl' ?>




<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
 http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">

<responseDate>2016-05-06T19:59:36Z</responseDate>

<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="5" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://oai.ukdataservice.ac.uk/oai/provider</request>



<GetRecord>

  <record>

  

    <header>

      <identifier>5</identifier>

      <datestamp>2016-05-06T12:37:59Z</datestamp>

      <setSpec>DataCollections</setSpec> 	

    </header>

	

    <metadata>

	<oai_dc:dc xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5"
           xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
           xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
           xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
   <dc:identifier>5</dc:identifier>
   <dc:title>Membership of Tribunals, 1971-1972</dc:title>
   <dc:creator>Hawker, G.N., University of Birmingham. Institute of Judicial Administration</dc:creator>
   <dc:creator>Newton, D., University of Birmingham. Institute of Judicial Administration</dc:creator>
   <dc:creator>Sumorok, E., University of Birmingham. Institute of Judicial Administration</dc:creator>
   <dc:creator>Cavenagh, W.E., University of Birmingham. Institute of Judicial Administration</dc:creator>
   <dc:subject>1972</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>ADMINISTRATIVE TRIBUNALS</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>APPEALS (LEGAL)</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>ENGLAND AND WALES</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>EXPERIENCE</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>FEES</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>GENDER</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>INCOME</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>JOB SATISFACTION</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>MEMBERSHIP</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>PERSONALITY</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>QUALIFICATIONS</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>RECRUITMENT</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>SOCIAL SECURITY</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>TRADE UNION MEMBERSHIP</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>VOLUNTARY WORK</dc:subject>
   <dc:subject>Elites and leadership - Social stratification and groupings</dc:subject>
   <dc:description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract copyright UK Data Service and data collection copyright owner.&lt;/p&gt;The aim of this study was to identify the social characteristics of members of selected administrative tribunals, to compare the members with other citizens involved in public service and to explain the criteria and practical means by which members are selected, or select themselves.</dc:description>
   <dc:description>&lt;B&gt;Main Topics&lt;/B&gt;:&lt;br&gt; Attitudinal/Behavioural Questions&lt;br&gt;
The survey assesses member's prior knowledge of, and familiarity with, the work of Appeals Tribunals and method of choice of members (i.e. whether through personal application or through suggestion of individual or organisation). Respondents are asked for their opinion of reasons for their selection, and whether they were appointed as Minister's nominee or as Trades Council nominee. If the member has been promoted to Chairman since his appointment, the importance of remuneration is obtained. If he is an ordinary member, the importance of fee for service and any eventual financial loss to the member through service are ascertained.&lt;br&gt;
Respondent, opinion on frequency of sittings of tribunals, necessary experience, qualifications and personal qualities required of a good chairman and effective ordinary member, and own personal satisfaction or dissatisfaction in service are elicited. In a final section, comments are invited on methods of recruiting and selecting members, on changes needed in kinds of people appointed, and on the general work of Tribunals.&lt;br&gt;
Background Variables&lt;br&gt;
Age, highest formal education or professional qualifications, status of employment (i.e. whether self-employed, employed, retired or housewife), last paid occupation, husband's occupation (if housewife), judicial or semi-judicial or committee experience (with details and dates), membership of professional, occupational or trade union organisations and any voluntary work done during the period, 1962 - 72. A final detailed breakdown of income and salary from all sources completes the information.</dc:description>
   <dc:date>1974</dc:date>
   <dc:format>Various</dc:format>
   <dc:language>English</dc:language>
   <dc:coverage>(Data Collection) From September 1971</dc:coverage>
   <dc:coverage>(Data Collection) To October 1972</dc:coverage>
   <dc:coverage>Geographical coverage: England and Wales</dc:coverage>
   <dc:rights>No information recorded</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
	

    </metadata>

  </record>

</GetRecord>



</OAI-PMH>









 



